Guide to the Robert A. M. Stern Architects Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Robert A. M. Stern Architects records
1954-2009
MS 1859
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
770.52
(968 boxes)
The records consist of project files, drawings, images, and a small number of models of projects undertaken by Robert A. M. Stern Architects, LLP, as well as professional and personal correspondence, writings, lecture transcripts and notes, and television programming created by founding partner Robert A. M. Stern.
Stern, Robert A. M., 1939-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Robert A. M. Stern Architects, LLP, 2005-2007, 2009, 2010, 2011, 2012, 2014, and 2016.
Conditions Governing Access
Records, except when noted as restricted, are open for research. Access restrictions are listed in both the Project Indexes and Project Records Inventories.
Requests for access to restricted records should be sent to the Manager of Archives and Records at Robert A. M. Stern Architects, LLP.
Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
Arrangement
The records were arranged by staff of Robert A. M. Stern Architects, LLP. Material was received in a number of chronological accessions consisting of either project records or professional and personal records. Records for all accessions are listed within this inventory, except for the first three accessions of Project Records (2006-M-010, 2007-M-094, and 2009-M-066), for which there are corresponding project indexes linked to this inventory.
Across accessions, there are multiple inter-related projects. Whenever possible "See Also" references have been included.
Biographical / Historical
Robert A.M. Stern Architects, LLP, is a 220-person firm of architects, interior designers, and supporting staff. It was founded in 1977. The firm has established an international reputation as a leading design firm with wide experience in residential, commercial, and institutional work. The firm has earned international recognition, numerous awards and citations for design excellence, including National Honor Awards of the American Institute of Architects.
Robert A. M. Stern, founder and senior partner in the firm of Robert A.M. Stern Architects of New York City, is a Fellow of the American Institute of Architects and received the Medal of Honor in 1984 and the President's Award in 2001 from its New York chapter. In 2002 he received the President's Medal from the Architectural League of New York and in 2008 was the tenth recipient of the Vincent Scully Prize from the National Building Museum. Prior to becoming dean of the Yale School of Architecture in 1998, Stern was a professor of architecture and director of the Preservation program at the Graduate School of Architecture, Planning, and Preservation at Columbia University. He served from 1984 to 1988 as the first director of Columbia's Temple Hoyne Buell Center for the Study of American Architecture. Stern has lectured extensively in the United States and abroad on both historical and contemporary topics in architecture. He is the author of several books, including New Directions in American Architecture; George Howe: Toward a Modern American Architecture; and Modern Classicism. Stern's interest and experience in the development of New York City's architecture and urbanism can be seen in books he has coauthored: New York 1880, New York 1900, New York 1930, New York 1960, and New York 2000. In 1981, Stern hosted Pride of Place: Building the American Dream, an eight-part, eight-hour documentary television series aired on PBS. In the fall of 2001, Stern lectured at Yale as the William Clyde DeVane Professor.
Sources: Firm information courtesy of Robert A. M. Stern Architects, LLP. Biographical information courtesy of Yale School of Architecture.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of project files, drawings, images, and a small number of models of projects undertaken by Robert A. M. Stern Architects, LLP, as well as professional and personal correspondence, writings, lecture transcripts and notes, and television programming created by founding partner Robert A. M. Stern.
Other Finding Aids
For the first three accessions of Project Records (2006-M-010, 2007-M-094, and 2009-M-066), please consult the project indexes (linked to the finding aid), which provide a list of projects for each accession and indicate the box numbers in which project materials are located.
Architecture -- United States -- History -- 20th Century; Architecture, American -- 20th Century; Architecture, Domestic; Commercial buildings; Stern, Robert A. M., 1939-; Robert A.M. Stern Architects
- Project records for 1966-1979, Accession 2006-M-010
  Other Finding Aids
  For a list of projects and the boxes in which project materials for this accession are located, please consult the Project Index.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Researchers must receive permission to use restricted records. Requests for access to restricted records should be sent to the Manager of Archive Services at Robert A. M. Stern Architects, LLP. Project records with access restrictions are noted in the Project Index.
  - Robert A.M. Stern Apartment I, 25 Central Park West [aka Tower Apartment], 1966-1968
    Scope and Contents
    Job number: 66001
    Job location: New York, NY
    - Publicity materials (Box 2)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 81)
    - Construction drawings (Box 81)
  - Robert A.M. Stern Apartment II, 101 Central Park West, 1967-1968
    Job number: 67002
    - Job files (Box 2)
    - Publicity materials (Box 2)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 159)
  - Wiseman House, 1965-1967
    Job number: 67003
    Job location: Montauk, NY
    - Correspondence (Box 2)
    - Job files (Box 2)
    - Publicity materials (Box 2)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 82)
    - Construction drawings (Box 82)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 82)
  - Fucigna Salon, 1967
    Job number: 67293
    Job location: Washington, D.C.
    - Job files (Box 58)
  - Gimbel Apartment, 1968-1971
    Job number: 68004
    - Correspondence (Box 2)
    - Job files (Box 2)
    - Publicity materials (Box 2)
    - Construction drawings (Box 83)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 83)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 159)
  - Robert A.M. Stern House I, 1968-1969
    Job number: 69005
    Job location: East Hampton, NY
    - Correspondence (Box 58)
    - Publicity materials (Box 58)
    - Construction drawings (Box 145)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 145)
  - Tiffeau-Busch Office & Showroom, 1969-1970
    Job number: 69006
    - Correspondence (Box 2)
    - Job files (Box 2)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 85)
  - Wiseman Apartments, 1969-1978
    Job number: 69266
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Job files (Box 3)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 62)
    - Construction drawings (Box 62)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 62)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 159)
  - Showrooms for Don Sophisticates, 1969
    Job number: 69273
    - Job files (Box 58)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 140)
  - Carol Gimbel Lebworth House interiors, 1969
    Job number: 69274
    Job location: Castellaras de Vieux, France
    - Job files (Box 58)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 140)
  - Earnest Brown House renovation, 1971-1975
    Job number: 69275
    Job location: Pleasantville, NY
    - Job files (Box 58)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 58)
  - Sommerfield Apartment, 1969-1970
    Job number: 70007
    - Job files (Box 3)
    - Publicity materials (Box 3)
  - Showrooms for Charlie's Girls and Hang Ten, 1969-1970
    Job number: 70009
    - Job files (Box 3, Box 85)
    - Publicity materials (Box 3)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 85)
    - Construction drawings (Box 85)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 85)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 85)
  - Immes Office Addition, 1969-1970
    Job number: 70010
    - Job files (Box 3)
    - Construction drawings (Box 84)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 84)
    - Presentation drawings (Box 84)
  - Gassel Apartment, 1969-1970
    Job number: 70011
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Job files (Box 3)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 86)
    - Construction drawings (Box 86)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 86)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 159)
  - Jenkins House, 1969-1970
    Job number: 70012
    - Job files (Box 4)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 87)
    - Construction drawings (Box 87)
    - Presentation drawings (Box 87)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 159)
  - Levine House, 1970-1971
    Job number: 70013
    Job location: Hewlett Bay Park, NY
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
    - Job files (Box 4)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 80)
    - Construction drawings (Box 80)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 80)
    - Site/landscape drawings (Box 80)
    - Presentation drawings (Box 80)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 4, Box 159)
    - Photographs (Box 4)
  - White/Hoffman Apartment, 1971
    Job number: 71014
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
    - Job files (Box 4)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 79)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 79)
    - Construction drawings (Box 79)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 79)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 159)
  - Kozmopolitan Gallery, 1970
    Job number: 71015
    - Job files (Box 4)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 78)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 78)
    - Construction drawings (Box 78)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 159)
  - "Another Chance for Cities" exhibit, 1970
    Job number: 71016
    - Correspondence (Box 52)
    - Job files (Box 52–53)
    - Publicity materials (Box 52)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 144)
    - Construction drawings (Box 144)
  - Roberts Apartment, 1971-1973
    Job number: 71017
    - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - Job files (Box 1)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 77)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 77)
    - Construction drawings (Box 77)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 77)
    - Site/landscape drawings (Box 77, Box 159)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 1, Box 159)
  - Koz Apartment, 1971
    Job number: 71018
    - Job files (Box 1)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 76)
  - Danziger Pool House, 1970-1971
    Job number: 71019
    Job location: Purchase, NY
    - Job files (Box 1)
    - Publicity materials (Box 1)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 75)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 75)
    - Construction drawings (Box 75)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 75)
    - Site/landscape drawings (Box 75)
    - Presentation drawings (Box 75)
  - Pranx Showroom, 1971
    Job number: 71020
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 68)
  - Hoffmann Apartment, 1971-1972
    Job number: 71021
    - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - Job files (Box 1)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 69)
    - Construction drawings (Box 69)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 69)
    - Presentation drawings (Box 69)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 159)
  - Geary Brownstone, 1971
    Job number: 72022
    - Job files (Box 1)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 70)
    - Construction drawings (Box 70)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 70)
    - Photographs (Box 1)
  - Beebe House, 1971-1974
    Job number: 72023
    - Correspondence (Box 5–6)
    - Job files (Box 5–6)
    - Publicity materials (Box 6)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 71, Box 74)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 71, Box 73–74)
    - Construction drawings (Box 67, Box 72–74)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 73–74)
    - Site/landscape drawings (Box 71)
    - Presentation drawings (Box 67, Box 71, Box 74)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 159)
    - Photographs (Box 6)
  - Kretchmer Apartment, 1971-1972
    Job number: 72024
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
    - Job files (Box 6)
    - Publicity materials (Box 6)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 66)
    - Construction drawings (Box 66)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 66)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 159)
    - Photographs (Box 6)
    - Slides (Box 152)
  - Diamond Greenhouse, 1971-1973
    Job number: 72025
    - Job files (Box 7)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 65)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 65)
    - Construction drawings (Box 65)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 65)
  - Kardon House, 1971-1973
    Job number: 72026
    Job location: Gladwyne, PA
    - Correspondence (Box 7)
    - Job files (Box 7–8)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 93)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 93)
    - Construction drawings (Box 93)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 93)
    - Site/landscape drawings (Box 93)
    - Presentation drawings (Box 93)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 159)
  - Parker Residence, 1971-1972
    Job number: 72027
    Job location: Bedford, NY
    - Correspondence (Box 8)
    - Job files (Box 8)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 64)
    - Site/landscape drawings (Box 64)
    - Presentation drawings (Box 64)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 161)
  - Ross Apartment, 1971
    Job number: 72028
    - Correspondence (Box 8)
    - Publicity materials (Box 8)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 63)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 63)
    - Construction drawings (Box 63)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 161)
    - Photographs (Box 8)
  - Danziger Apartment, 1971-1974
    Job number: 72029
    - Correspondence (Box 8)
    - Job files (Box 8–9)
    - Publicity materials (Box 8)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 94)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 94)
    - Construction drawings (Box 94)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 94)
    - Presentation drawings (Box 94)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 161)
    - Photographs (Box 8)
  - Beebe Townhouse, 1971-1973
    Job number: 72030
    - Correspondence (Box 9)
    - Job files (Box 9)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 96)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 161)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 96)
    - Lighting drawings (Box 96)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 161)
    - Photographs (Box 9)
  - Solinger House, 1971-1973
    Job number: 72031
    Job location: Greenwich, CT
    - Correspondence (Box 9)
    - Job files (Box 9)
    - Publicity materials (Box 9)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 136)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 61, Box 136)
    - Construction drawings (Box 61)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 61)
    - Site/landscape drawings (Box 61, Box 136)
    - Lighting drawings (Box 61)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 161)
    - Photographs (Box 9)
    - Slides (Box 168)
  - Eisner Apartment, 1972-1975
    Job number: 72033
    - Correspondence (Box 9)
    - Job files (Box 9–10)
    - Publicity materials (Box 10)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 95)
    - Construction drawings (Box 95)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 95)
    - Photographs (Box 10)
  - Howard Apartment, 1972-1976
    Job number: 72035
    - Correspondence (Box 11)
    - Job files (Box 11)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 143)
    - Construction drawings (Box 96, Box 143)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 158)
  - Burns Greenhouse, 1972-1973
    Job number: 72036
    - Correspondence (Box 11)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 96)
    - Construction drawings (Box 96)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 96)
  - Mercer House, 1972-1975
    Job number: 72037
    - Correspondence (Box 12)
    - Job files (Box 12)
    - Publicity materials (Box 12)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 97)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 97)
    - Construction drawings (Box 92, Box 97)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 97)
    - Site/landscape drawings (Box 92, Box 97)
    - Lighting drawings (Box 97)
    - Presentation drawings (Box 97)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 158)
    - Photographs (Box 12)
    - Slides (Box 168)
  - Millstein Townhouse, 1972-1979
    Job number: 72038
    - Correspondence (Box 13)
    - Job files (Box 13–15)
    - Publicity materials (Box 15)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 91)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 91)
    - Construction drawings (Box 90–91)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 90)
    - Site/landscape drawings (Box 90)
    - Lighting drawings (Box 90)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 158)
    - Slides (Box 168)
  - South Apartment, 1972
    Job number: 72039
    - Correspondence (Box 16)
    - Job files (Box 16)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 89)
    - Construction drawings (Box 89)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 89)
  - House Beautiful Living Center, 1973
    Job number: 72040
    - Correspondence (Box 16)
    - Job files (Box 16)
    - Publicity materials (Box 16)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 89)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 158)
    - Photographs (Box 16)
  - Carter Apartment, 1972
    Job number: 72270
    - Correspondence (Box 16)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 99)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 99)
  - Ross Apartment, 1973
    Job number: 73267
    - Correspondence (Box 16–17)
    - Job files (Box 16–17)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 98)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 98)
    - Construction drawings (Box 98)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 98)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 98, Box 158)
  - Solinger Apartment, 1973
    Job number: 73268
    Job location: Delray Beach, FL
    - Correspondence (Box 17)
    - Job files (Box 17)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 98)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 98)
    - Construction drawings (Box 98)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 98)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 158)
  - Schulte Residence, 1973
    Job number: 73271
    Job location: Palm Beach, FL
    - Correspondence (Box 17)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 99)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 99)
    - Construction drawings (Box 99)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 158)
  - Arnold House renovation, 1973
    Job number: 73276
    - Job files (Box 58)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 141)
  - Chapnick House renovation, 1973-1974
    Job number: 73277
    Job location: Larchmont, NY
    - Correspondence (Box 58)
    - Construction drawings (Box 58, Box 140)
  - USDAN Center design competition, 1973
    Job number: 73278
    - Job files (Box 58)
  - Marks/Friedman Apartment, 1973
    Job number: 74041
    - Job files (Box 18)
    - Construction drawings (Box 89)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 89)
  - Source Equities Offices, 1973-1974
    Job number: 74042
    - Correspondence (Box 18)
    - Job files (Box 18)
    - Publicity materials (Box 18)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 88)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 88)
    - Construction drawings (Box 88)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 88)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 158)
    - Photographs (Box 18)
    - Slides (Box 168)
  - Hagmann and Stern Offices, 200 W. 70th Street, 1973-1974
    Job number: 74043
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 100)
    - Construction drawings (Box 100)
    - Presentation drawings (Box 100)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 158)
  - Godsick Apartment, 1973
    Job number: 74044
    - Correspondence (Box 18)
    - Job files (Box 18)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 158)
    - Construction drawings (Box 100)
  - Aguilera Apartment, 1974
    Job number: 74045
    - Correspondence (Box 19)
    - Job files (Box 19)
    - Publicity materials (Box 19)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 100, Box 158)
    - Construction drawings (Box 100)
  - Beebe Walker Apartment, 1974
    Job number: 74046
    - Job files (Box 20)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 147)
  - Lang House, 1973-1974
    Job number: 74047
    Job location: Washington, CT
    - Correspondence (Box 20)
    - Job files (Box 20)
    - Publicity materials (Box 20)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 100)
    - Construction drawings (Box 100)
    - Presentation drawings (Box 100)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 158)
    - Photographs (Box 20)
    - Slides (Box 168)
  - Bourke House, 1973-1974
    Job number: 74048
    - Correspondence (Box 21)
    - Job files (Box 21–22)
    - Publicity materials (Box 21)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 103)
    - Construction drawings (Box 104)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 104)
    - Site/landscape drawings (Box 104–105)
    - Presentation drawings (Box 103)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 158)
    - Photographs (Box 21)
  - Taft Apartment, 1974
    Job number: 74049
    - Correspondence (Box 22)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 101)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 160)
  - Cullman House, 1975
    Job number: 74050
    Job location: North Stamford, CT
    - Correspondence (Box 22)
    - Job files (Box 22–23, Box 57)
    - Publicity materials (Box 23)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 101)
    - Construction drawings (Box 101, Box 141)
    - Site/landscape drawings (Box 101)
    - Presentation drawings (Box 160)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 160)
    - Photographs (Box 23)
    - Slides (Box 168)
  - Kastner Apartment, 1975
    Job number: 74051
    Job location: Elkins Park, PA
    - Job files (Box 23)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 102)
    - Construction drawings (Box 102)
    - Furniture/millwork drawings (Box 102)
    - Presentation drawings (Box 102)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 160)
    - Slides (Box 168)
  - Stephen Brown Kitchen, 1974
    Job number: 74052
    - Correspondence (Box 23)
  - Ehrman House, 1974-1976
    Job number: 74053
    Job location: Westchester County, NY
    - Correspondence (Box 23)
    - Job files (Box 23–26)
    - Publicity materials (Box 26)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 106)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 106–108, Box 160)
    - Construction drawings (Box 107–108)
    - Site/landscape drawings (Box 106)
    - Presentation drawings (Box 107–108, Box 160)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 160)
    - Photographs (Box 26)
    - Slides (Box 149–151, Box 168)
  - Arlen/Olympic Tower: Model Apartment, 1974
    Job number: 74054
    - Correspondence (Box 27)
    - Job files (Box 27)
    - Publicity materials (Box 27)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 109)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 109)
    - Construction drawings (Box 109)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 160)
    - Photographs (Box 27)
    - Slides (Box 168)
  - Bernstein renovation, 1974
    Job number: 74279
    - Correspondence (Box 58)
    - Job files (Box 58)
    - Publicity materials (Box 58)
    - Existing conditions/measured drawings (Box 136)
    - Design development/schematic drawings (Box 158)
    - Sketches/small drawings (Box 136, Box 158)
    - Photographs (Box 58)
  - Newburger-Loeb Office renovation, 1974-1975
    Job number: 74280
    - Correspondence (Box 59)
    - Job files (Box 59)
  - Leonard Stern Townhouse, 1975
    Job number: 75055
    - Correspondence (Box 27–28)
    - Job files (Box 27–30)
    - Publicity materials (Box 30)